<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Milky Quartz, a note garden 🌱🖥️</title>
      <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Milky Quartz, a note garden 🌱🖥️</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>CSS</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/css</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/css</guid>
    <description>CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) CSS reset - a method of resetting default styling of some HTML tag, used by most browsers. It can be done, for example, like this: html, body, div, span, applet, object, iframe, h1, h2, h3, h4, h5, h6, p, blockquote, pre, a, abbr, acronym, address, big, cite, code, del, dfn, em, img, ins, kbd, q, s, samp, small, strike, strong, sub, sup, tt, var, b, u, i, center, dl, dt, dd, ol, ul, li, fieldset, form, label, legend, table, caption, tbody, tfoot, thead, tr, th, td, article, aside, canvas, details, embed, figure, figcaption, footer, header, hgroup, menu, nav, output, ruby, section, summary, time, mark, audio, video { margin: 0; padding: 0; border: 0; font-size: 100%; font: inherit; vertical-align: baseline; }.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:55:44 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>OpenGraph</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/opengraph</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/opengraph</guid>
    <description>OpenGraph Protocol OpenGraph Protocol or OGP is a web standard for other web applications to create embedded content of your link. The simplest way to add OGP embed to your website, is to add this to its &lt;head&gt; tag: &lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;netcatcat.net : subsite&quot;&gt; &lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;&gt; &lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;netcatcat.net/subsite&quot;&gt; &lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;netcatcat.net/assets/images/KBITY_TRANSEDEN_TEAL_HEHE_.png&quot;&gt;.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Deploying EC2 with... everything.</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/aws-ec2-tf-cf</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/aws-ec2-tf-cf</guid>
    <description>Let’s get straight to business. What do we want to do? Deploy an AWS EC2 instance in a fantastically diverse collection of ways. Not including clicking through things in a web UI (that’s cool but too slow and too easy, thus very boring) nor especially pulling an untrustworthy LLM-generated YAML or Bash script from Amazon Q itself (or loose sequence of 3 commands, to be more precise).</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Firewalls on Linux</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/firewalls</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/firewalls</guid>
    <description>firewalld Firewall. ufw AKA uncomplicated firewall; a firewall config tool running on top of iptables. Common with Ubuntu-based distros (e.g. Linux Mint).</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Kubernetes theory</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/kubernetes-theory</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/kubernetes-theory</guid>
    <description>Kubernetes For more low-level practical stuff, go to docs on Docker and K8s basics. For what reason? [].</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Minikube &amp; K8s basics</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/minikube</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/minikube</guid>
    <description>Minikube A lot of starter stuff here follows from starter Go+Docker stuff at Docker basics. Deploying a Go helowoorld on Minikube First off, ensure you have Docker installed and Docker group set up.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>PGP&amp;GPG</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/pgp</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/pgp</guid>
    <description>PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) Pretty good tool for encryption &amp; decryption, as well as verifying file integrity. GPG/GnuPG tool Gnu Privacy Guard - the best free tool (afaik) for doing things with PGP.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Prometheus</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/prometheus</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/prometheus</guid>
    <description>Prometheus Prometheus is a tool for collecting data for monitoring purposes. Basically it’s one of the “backend options” for monitoring visualization tools such as Grafana.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>robots.txt</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/robots.txt</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/robots.txt</guid>
    <description>robots.txt A semi-informal standard made by Google to tell webscraping robots (provided they are polite; some aren’t) to fuck off. See official Google documentation here.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>SRE principles</title>
    <link>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/sre-principles</link>
    <guid>https://milky-quartz.netcatcat.net/sre-principles</guid>
    <description>SRE principles Monitoring Concepts from João Pereira’s 52 weeks of SRE (W2) Black-box and white-box A name familiar from testing concepts; we can also categorize monitoring into ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>